[
    {
        "question": "1. What is the difference between end users and customers?",
        "answer": "End User: An end user or an end customer directly receives the service or employs the product. End users are not the only customers as there may be intermediate entities like purchasing departments, whose expectations or needs must be carried forward through a series of service contracts or requirement definitions.\nCustomer: A customer may or may not have the ability to choose between different products and suppliers. For instance, in monopoly situations like local telephone and cable television services, there are scenarios when end users do not make the purchasing decision. It may include clients of social service agencies, court-appointed lawyers, or employees of an organization where the purchasing department makes choices.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is a service request?",
        "answer": "A service request is a formal request submitted by a user for some types of services, software, or hardware. A service request generally refers to something the user wants and/or needs but does not already have, such as a printer or a laptop. It often involves items that are already approved. For instance, if it is a company policy that all employees get access to the cloud-based CRM system and when someone from the marketing department sends a service request for the access, then this does not need any additional approval. The IT help desk can simply fulfill this request.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is ISO/IEC 27002?",
        "answer": "ISO/IEC 27002:2013 gives guidelines for organizational information security standards and information security management practices including selection, implementation, and management of controls, taking into consideration the organization’s information security risk environment(s). It is designed to be used by organizations that intend to:\nSelect controls within the process of implementing an Information Security Management System based on ISO/IEC 27001\nImplement commonly accepted information security controls\nDevelop their independent information security management guidelines",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are the different knowledge management systems?",
        "answer": "Different knowledge management systems are given below.\nCMIS (Capacity Management Information System): CMIS is a collection of IT infrastructure usage, capacity, and performance information that is gathered in a consistent manner and stored in one or more databases. It is a single book of records of IT infrastructure usage, capacity, and performance data, complete with associated business, application, and service statistics. Any IT staff who needs access to capacity management data can potentially use a CMIS.\nAMIS (Availability Management Information System): It is a virtual repository of all Availability Management data, usually stored in multiple physical locations.\nKEDB (Known Error Database): A known error is a problem that has a documented root cause and a workaround. Known errors are managed throughout their life cycle by the Problem Management process. The details of each known error are recorded in a Known Error Record stored in the Known Error Database (KEDB).\nCMDB (Configuration Management Database): CMDB is a database that contains all relevant information about the components of the information system used in an organization’s IT services and the relationships between those components. CMDB provides an organized view of data and a means of examining the data from any desired perspective. Within this context, components of an information system are referred to as configuration items (CIs). A CI can be any conceivable IT component, including software, hardware, documentation, and personnel, as well as any combination of them. The processes of configuration management specify, control, and track configuration items and any changes made to them in a comprehensive and systematic fashion.\nDML (Definitive Media Library): DML is a secure compound in which the definitive, authorized versions of software package configuration items (CIs) are stored and protected. It consists of one or more software libraries or file-storage areas referred to as repositories.\nSKMS (Service Knowledge Management System): ITIL Knowledge Management aims at gathering, analyzing, storing, and sharing knowledge and information within an organization. The primary purpose of Knowledge Management is to improve efficiency by reducing the need to rediscover knowledge.\nBecome a master of Artificial Intelligence by going through this online AI Course in Toronto!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the ITIL-based models adopted by an organization?",
        "answer": "MOF: Microsoft Operations Framework (MOF) is a series of 23 documents that guide IT professionals through the processes of creating, implementing, and managing efficient and cost-effective services.\nHewlett Packard (HP ITSM Reference Model): This model is a significant tool useful in presenting and describing several management processes, inter-process relationships, and business linkages that IT needs to put in place for successful development, deployment, and support of services in the e-world.\nIBM (IT Process Model ): This is an industry template that enables you to define common business processes and services across the enterprise. The software consists of a set of business process models and service definitions to support core system renewal and integration projects.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is the relation between availability percentage, availability service time, and downtime?",
        "answer": "Availability % = (Available service time – downtime)/Available service time\nIt is used to ensure that all IT services are available and are functioning correctly whenever customers want to use them in the framework of SLAs in force.\nGet certified from this top AI Course in Singapore now!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is ITIL, and what is its primary purpose?",
        "answer": "ITIL is defined as an Information Technology Infrastructure Library;  it is primarily used to provide a set of best practices for the IT sector in terms of Service Management and is more focused on aligning the needs of the business to enhance the services.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is the concept of a service desk in ITIL?",
        "answer": "A service desk is a center of contact for users to request IT support, report incidents, and make service requests. It is the point of communication between users and IT service providers.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Differentiate between an incident and a problem in ITIL?",
        "answer": "An interruption in an IT service or degradation in the performance of the IT service is called an Incident. A problem, on the other hand, is the cause of one or more incidents, and it is the identification of a root cause.\n\nITIL Interview Questions for Intermediate",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. How does ITIL help minimize the total cost of ownership (TCO) for IT investments?",
        "answer": "IT investments and staff always find that they break their work schedule. This happens because the unscheduled work always takes priority over the work that is planned. ITIL can help an organization stop this continuous cycle and can, therefore, help employees focus on the total cost of ownership (TCO) and other activities in their respective departments.\nExplore these Project Management Interview Questions and ace your next interview with ease!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Is there a trade-off between return and risk?",
        "answer": "According to modern portfolio theory, there is a trade-off between risk and return. All other factors being equal, if a particular investment incurs a higher risk of financial loss for prospective investors, those investors must be able to expect a higher return in order to be attracted to the higher risk. In the majority of cases, even though there is no promise of higher returns on risky assets, the higher risk just tends to scare off potential investors, keeping the returns on a given investment low. The only investments that can really try to promise higher returns for higher risk are bonds, and even then the higher returns won’t be generated if the issuing organization goes default.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Which two service management processes will most likely use risk analysis and management methodology?",
        "answer": "The two service management processes are Availability Management and IT Service Continuity Management. ITIL Availability Management aims at defining, analyzing, planning, measuring, and improving all aspects of the availability of IT services. Availability Management is responsible for ensuring that all IT infrastructure, processes, tools, roles, etc. are appropriate for the agreed availability targets. IT Service Continuity Management (ITSCM) aims at managing risks that could seriously impact IT services. ITSCM ensures that the IT service provider can always provide the minimum agreed service levels, by reducing the risk from disaster events to an acceptable level and planning for the recovery of IT services. ITSCM should be designed to support Business Continuity Management.\nLearn more about Artificial Intelligence in this AI Training in New York to get ahead in your career!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What type of information is stored in a CMDB?",
        "answer": "CMDB contains contents intended to hold a collection of IT assets commonly referred to as configuration items (CI), as well as descriptive relationships between such assets. When populated, the repository becomes a means of understanding how critical assets such as information systems are composed, what their upstream sources or dependencies are, and what their downstream targets are.\nAre you interested in learning Artificial Intelligence from experts? Enroll in the AI Course in Bangalore now!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Explain Service Portfolio, Service Catalog, and Service Pipeline.",
        "answer": "Service Portfolio: It defines services provided by service providers across the market and all customers. The objective of ITIL Service Portfolio Management is to manage the Service Portfolio. Service Portfolio Management ensures that the service provider has the right mix of services to meet the required business outcomes at an appropriate level of investment.\nService Catalogue is a subset of Service Portfolio. Services ready to be offered to customers are listed in this catalog. An IT Service Catalog is a list of available technology resources and offerings within an organization.\nService Pipeline consists of services under development. It is a great opportunity to view the direction of a service provider’s growth as it discusses and includes the future services that are currently under development by the service provider.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is the difference between ITIL v2 and v3?",
        "answer": "The ITIL v2 library was organized into seven core books:\n(i) Service Support\n(ii) Service Delivery\n(iii) ICT Infrastructure Management\n(iv) Planning to Implement Service Management\n(v) Application Management\n(vi) Business Perspective\n(vii) Security Management\nOn the other hand, ITIL v3 is now organized into just five books:\n(i) Service Strategy\n(ii) Service Design\n(iii) Service Transition\n(iv) Service Operation\n(v) Continual Service Improvement\nBasically, the v2 process areas have been logically grouped into a phased life cycle approach\nIn contrast to ITIL v2, ITIL v3 clearly defines the roles and responsibilities in each process and reasons the role of communication in the entire life cycle.\nInterested in learning Artificial Intelligence? Check out the AI Training in Sydney!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Who decides the categorization of a proposed change within an ITIL Change Management process?",
        "answer": "It is the task of the Change Manager. A Change Manager plays a key role in ensuring that the projects (change initiatives) meet their objectives within timelines and the said budgets by increasing employee adoption and usage. This person will focus on the people-side changes, including changes that happen to business processes, systems and technologies, job roles, and organization structures.\nLearn more about Artificial Intelligence in this insightful AI blog!\n\nITIL Interview Questions for Experienced",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What is a plan-do-check-act (PDSA) cycle?",
        "answer": "The PDSA cycle is a systematic series of steps for gaining valuable learning and knowledge for the continual improvement of a product or process. Also known as the Deming Wheel or Deming Cycle, the concept and application of the PDSA cycle was first introduced to Dr. Deming by his mentor, Walter Shewhart of the famous Bell Laboratories in New York.\nthe four phases of the plan-do-check-act cycle are as follows:  \nPlan: Identifying and analyzing the problem\nDo: Developing and testing a potential solution\nCheck: Measuring how effective the test solution was and analyzing whether it could be improved in any way\n Act: Implementing the improved solution fully\nIf you want to learn Artificial Intelligence in-depth, check out this AI tutorial!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What type of information is captured in an information security policy?",
        "answer": "Information security policies are the documented business and technical rules for protecting an organization from information security risks faced by its business and technical infrastructure. These written policy documents provide a high-level description of various controls, which the organization will use to manage its information security risks.\nThe information security policy documents are also considered to be a formal declaration of the management’s intent to protect its information assets from relevant risks. In specific cases, the policies are supported by information security procedures that identify key activities required to implement relevant information security policies.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What is a balanced scorecard?",
        "answer": "A balanced scorecard is a strategic planning and management system that is used extensively in business, government, and nonprofit organizations worldwide to align business activities to the vision and strategy of an organization, improve internal and external communications, and monitor the organization’s performance against its strategic goals.\nLearn all AI concepts through the AI Course in Hyderabad to take your career to a whole new level!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Suppose a Service Level Manager requires confirmation regarding the time (say, within 10 seconds) taken by the internal Service Desk to answer a certain percentage of calls. In what document would the Service Desk’s agreement to this requirement be recorded?",
        "answer": "The Operational-level Agreement (OLA) is a contract that defines how various IT groups within a company plan to deliver a service or a set of services. OLAs are designed to address and solve the problem of IT silos by setting forth a specific set of criteria and defining a specific set of IT services to be performed by each department. It should be noted that the term ‘Service Level Agreement’ (SLA) is used in many companies while discussing the agreements between two internal groups. However, according to the Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) framework for best practices, this type of internal contracts is better known as  Operational-level Agreement.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Which ITIL process should ensure that the organization is aware of new and changing technologies?",
        "answer": "Capacity Management is responsible for ensuring that the organization is aware of new and changing technologies. It is the discipline that checks and verifies that IT infrastructure is provided at the right time in the right volume at the right price, with utmost efficiency. This requires inputs from many areas of the business to identify what services are (or will be) required, what IT infrastructure is needed to support these services, what level of contingency will be needed, and what the cost of this infrastructure will be.\nGo through the AI Course in London to get a clear understanding of Artificial Intelligence!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. How is IT Service Continuity Management (ITSCM) related to Business Continuity Planning (BCP)?",
        "answer": "IT Service Continuity is a subset of Business Continuity Planning (BCP) and encompasses both IT disaster recovery planning and wider IT resilience planning. It also incorporates those elements of IT infrastructure and services that relate to (voice) telephonic and data communications. It is a systematic process to prevent, predict, and manage Information and Communications Technology (ICT) disruption and incidents, which have the potential to disrupt ICT services, and it should result in a more resilient IT service capability aligned to wider organizational requirements.\nIf you have any doubts or queries related to Artificial Intelligence, get them clarified from the AI experts on our AI Community!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. After a change has been implemented, an evaluation is performed. What is this evaluation called?",
        "answer": "It is known as Post-implementation Review (PIR). PIR is an assessment and review of the complete working solution. It will be performed after a period of live running, sometimes after the project is completed. The Post-implementation Review is used to evaluate the effectiveness of the system development after the system has been in production for a specific period of time (usually 6 months). It is a free-form report, and not all sections of it are relevant or necessary to the final product. A description of the Post-implementation Review report is always produced.\nGo through the Project Management blog to get a clear understanding of Project Management!\nScenario Based on ITIL Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. Assume you have been appointed as the new IT service manager in a renowned company, along with adopting the ITIL implementation. Outline the steps you would take to initiate ITIL.",
        "answer": "In such a scenario, I would approach it with the below plan:\nAssessment and planning:  After conducting a thorough assessment of the prevalent IT service management process, including strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats, I would involve the stakeholders in the planning process to ensure buy-in and support. Develop a plan consisting of outlined goals, timelines, resources, requirements, and key performance indicators (KPIs) for measuring success.\nEducation training: Organizing training sessions and educating the employees regarding ITIL would be the most important part of the plan for adopting ITIL services.\nEstablishing Governance Structure: Define roles and responsibilities for the IT service team, including the appointment of a new advisory board (CAB).\nConfiguration Management Database (CMDB): Establish CMBD to centralize and manage information about relations and configuration items (CI).\nCommunication and Change Management: Communicate a comprehensive plan to keep stakeholders informed during the ITIL implementation process, including the objectives and progress.\nDevelop, maintain, and monitor the performance for the ITIL process against KPIs.\nConduct periodic reviews and audits for ITIL processes to ensure compliance.\nIf you want to learn the Dashboard of KPI in-depth, check out this Tableau KPI Dashboard!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. How would you organize and handle the issues related to frequent incidents related to service disruptions in an organization? Develop an implementation plan to resolve the issue through ITIL.",
        "answer": "To effectively handle issues related to service disruptions, it becomes crucial to develop and implement ITIL. The aim then becomes to minimize the impact of incidents on business operations.\nEnsure a centralized logging system to capture and categorize incident reports; define criteria for incident prioritization based on impact urgency. Ensure the logging of incidents with accurate details and information, including the effect, service, and user details.\nEnsure a trained team to handle incoming issues correctly. This team shall keep a regular check on different groups with issues to note how bad they are through diagnostic tools.\nDefine standard incident resolution procedures and prioritize their execution based on the severity of the issue faced.\nEstablish a clear communication path both for escalations and resolution in due time. Maintain proactive communication with stakeholders, including affected users.\nEnsure documentation of Incident closed and actions taken, analyze the root causes and lessons learned.\nIncident resolution and review analysis should be conducted regularly to identify trends and recurring issues with the areas for improvement.\nIncident management integration with other ITIL processes with the concerned stakeholders and cross-functional incident managers.\nGo through the SOP for Project Management to get a clear understanding of Project Management!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is ITIL?",
        "answer": "ITIL is a short form of Information Technology Infrastructure Library. It is a set of comprehensive practices and guidelines that helps software developers provide the best IT services according to the current market trends and requirements. Additionally, it helps businesses establish a competitive environment and achieve their goals in the best possible way, including better plan, management, and deliveries.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "We can compare ITIL with COBIT with the help of the following table:\nITIL COBIT\nIt is mainly used for ITSM (Information Technology Service Management). It is mainly used for IT integration.\nThe primary function of ITIL is to implement the guidelines of an organization. The primary function of COBIT is to derive guidelines for organizational operations.\nThe main application of ITL is process implementation. The main application of COBIT is process descriptions.\nIt has features like design, transitions, service strategies, operation implementations, etc. It provides features like control objectives, maturity models, management guidelines, etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) What are some advantages of using ITIL?",
        "answer": "The following are some advantages of ITIL:\nADVERTISEMENT\nADVERTISEMENT\nFinancial management\nBetter customer satisfaction\nBetter decision-making processes\nImproved service availability\nBetter control over infrastructure services\nBuilds a clear structure of an organization",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What are the processes involved in ITIL Service life cycle model?",
        "answer": "There are mainly five different processes involved in the ITIL Service life cycle model; they are:\nService Strategy: This process helps implement, define and maintain service strategies, rules, and policies.\nService Design: This process helps to design the processes to ensure the proper implementation of strategies.\nService Transition: This process helps form communication between projects and operations to effectively improve service quality for better service transitions.\nService Operation: This process helps create end-to-end process overflow to provide stable services to the end-user.\nContinual Service Improvement: This process is mainly used to improve service quality by adding new options and features to meet the current industry standards.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The following are the significant benefits of ITIL:\nProvides powerful alignment between the business and IT.\nIncreased customer satisfaction and better service deliveries.\nBetter utilization of resources, making it cost-effective.\nBetter control over business risks and service disruption.\nAn accessible and in-depth vision of a business' IT costs, including the assets.\nAvailability of quick business change for a controlled service environment.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The following are the primary responsibilities of the Incident management:\nIncident management ensures that appropriate methods and strategies are implemented for effective response, broad analysis, documentation, reporting incidents, and other ongoing management services.\nIt reports progress stats and connectivity options of incident management to support staff.\nIt sets priorities and activities efficiently.\nIt manages and controls user-experience with improved IT services.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What are some steps involved in the working of the Incident management system?",
        "answer": "The following are the steps involved in the working of Incident management system:\nRecords the incidents.\nCategorizes the incidents according to their impact and urgency.\nAuthorizes the incidents.\nProvides resolution and recovery after the occurrence of an incident.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What are the stages involved in incident management in ITIL?",
        "answer": "Incident management is a process that is mainly beneficial in managing and handling the lifecycle of reported incidents. There are many stages involved in incident management to resolve and document the incidents properly. The following are the stages that must be carried out throughout the lifecycle of incident management:\nIdentification of incident\nIncident logging\nIncident categorization\nIncident prioritization\nIncident response\nInitial diagnosis\nIncident escalation\nResolution and recovery\nIncident Closure",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What are some essential features of ITIL?",
        "answer": "The following are some essential features of ITIL:\nBased on a single language/terminology.\nDelivers consistent quality.\nSeveral existing activities and processes for optimizing them.\nFocuses on IT. However, it is not limited to IT only.\nAvailability of multiple related processes and roles (tasks).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What is meant by SLA?",
        "answer": "SLA is a short form of 'Service Level Agreement'. It is nothing but a proposal or an agreement signed between a service provider (includes internal or external both) and the end-user. The SLA consists of the different levels of services required by the service provider.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) How many types of service level agreements are there?",
        "answer": "There are three different types of service level agreements, such as:\nCustomer Service Level Agreements: This type of agreement is formed between the customer and the service provider.\nInternal Service Level Agreements: This type of agreement is formed between IT and internal customers (for example- any other department or site).\nVendor Service Level Agreements: This type of agreement is formed between the developer and the vendor.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The problem management in ITIL is mainly responsible for performing the followings:\nRecognizes and troubleshoot recurring incidents.\nDetermines the root cause of these occurrences.\nTakes appropriate action to prevent these incidents from reoccurring.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) What are the main steps involved in the problem management process?",
        "answer": "The following are the steps involved in the problem management process:\nProblem detection and logging\nCategorization of the problem and further prioritizing the problem\nInvestigation of the actual reason\nWorkaround a solution for a problem\nReport a known error stats\nProblem resolution\nProblem closure\nReviewing the problem",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) What is the use of event management in ITIL?",
        "answer": "The primary use of event management is to check configuration items and services and make sure that they are continually observed. Besides, event management can also filter and categorize events, which eventually helps to find any particular actions.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) What are the different service providers involved in the ITIL process?",
        "answer": "The following are the different service providers involved in the ITIL process:\nInternal Service Provider: ISP usually manages the internal business or an organization. It is a dedicated resource of the business unit that physically exists to fulfill the organization's needs.\nExternal Service Provider: ESP usually deals with the management of an external organization. It means that ESP offers IT services and features to external customers and fulfill their needs. It is not limited to any market, business, or individual.\nShared Services Unit: SSU usually acts as an extension of ISPs. This type of provider is considered an autonomous unit within the organization.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What is defined by the term Known Error?",
        "answer": "A Known Error is an identified problem that contains a recorded root cause and a solution. It mainly includes the followings:\nStatus of the error\nDescription of the error\nRoot cause of the error\nWorkaround (solution) of the error",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) What are the different knowledge management systems in ITIL?",
        "answer": "The following are some main knowledge management systems:\nDefinitive Media Library (DML)\nCapacity Management Information System (CMIS)\nKnown Error Database (KEDB)\nConfiguration Management Database (CMDB)\nService Knowledge Management System (SKMS)\nAvailability Management Information System (AMIS)",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What are the objectives of the IT service continuity management system?",
        "answer": "The main objectives of the IT service continuity management system are:\nIdentification of risks\nTesting the back-out situations\nFinalizing the entire back-out arrangements",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The following are the few benefits of the ITIL service desk implementation:\nBetter first call resolution\nBetter identification of trends and events\nImproved customer satisfaction\nBetter tracking of service quality\nQuick restoration of service\nSkill-based support\nBetter incident response time",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The following are the processes that are utilized by the service desk:\nWorkflow\nProcedures diagrams",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) What are some of the conditions to be followed to close any known error?",
        "answer": "A known error can be closed when any of the following conditions occur:\nWhen all the RFC (Request for Change) records are closed.\nWhen a record resides in the error closure stage.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) What is the primary function of Configuration Management in ITIL?",
        "answer": "The primary function of Configuration Management in ITIL is to receive, keep, manage, update and verify the data on IT assets and configuration in the organizations.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) How will you differentiate a service request from a change request?",
        "answer": "A service request is usually defined as the request formally submitted by the user to access IT services and change its standard. On the other hand, a change request is defined as the proposal to change any specific product or the entire system.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The term PDSA here is the short form of plan-do-check-act. It is a 4-step approach that is mainly used continuous improvements of any product or process in an enterprise. It is also known as the Deming cycle/wheel/circle.\nThe four phases can be explained as:\nPlan: Analyzing and identifying the current problem.\nDo: Developing the necessary solution for the problem.\n\nCheck: Testing a solution and checking how effectively it handles the problem. Additionally, finding other options that could be helpful in the improvements.\nAct: Implementing the final solution.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "A project is a limited time procedure in which work is done. Whereas, a process is continuous and does not include any specified end date.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The following are the few responsibilities of an ITL Service Desk:\nLog, classify and prioritize incidents.\nInvestigate the incidents\nResolve the incident\nManage major incidents\nIncident management reporting",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The following are the three ITIL models that are widely adopted by an organization:\nIBM (IT Process Model)\nMOF (Microsoft Operation Framework)\nHewlett-Packard (HP ITSM Reference Model)",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) How will you differentiate an end-user from a customer?",
        "answer": "End-User: An end-user (also called an end-customer) is the one who directly receives and accesses the service or uses the service or a product.\nCustomer: A customer may or may not have the authority to select between products and suppliers.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) How will you define an Incident and a Problem?",
        "answer": "Incident: It is usually defined as an event that is not part of a standard process. In other words, it is the event that causes unplanned interruption or disruption to an IT service.\nProblem: It is generally defined as the underlying cause of a conflict or chain of events.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) How will you differentiate proactive problem management from reactive problem management?",
        "answer": "The main function of proactive problem management is to stop incidents before happening by finding potential problems and IT infrastructure errors. On the other side, reactive problem management's main function is to identify and eliminate the main reasons of recognized incidents.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) What is the primary function of ITIL Change Management?",
        "answer": "Change management's primary function is to eliminate or reduce the risk in business processes and systems by establishing standardized procedures. It is one of the main tasks of the Change manager that is performed in an agile and effective manner. Additionally, it ensures that the projects satisfy their goals and essential requirements within the specified time and budget.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The following are the seven R's of Change Management:\nFirst, who RAISED the change?\nSecond, what is the REASON for the change?\nThird, what RETURN will the change deliver?\nFourth, what RISKS are there is we do or do not carry out the change?\nFifth, What RESOURCES will be required to perform this change?\nSixth, who is RESPONSIBLE for this change being performed?\nSeventh, what RELATIONSHIPS are there between this and other changes?",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) What is defined by the term PIR in the context of ITIL?",
        "answer": "The term PIR is a short form of 'Post Implementation Review'. PIR in ITIL is usually defined as the identification and examination of the complete working process, along with the solution. The post-implementation review evaluates the implementation's effectiveness after the change request is implemented into the system. It is a free-form review report that is generally processed once the live running session of the project has been done.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The primary goal of capacity management is to ensure that IT services and resources are appropriately sized to meet service level objectives for current and upcoming business needs in a cost-effective and timely manner.\nCapacity Management has three following sub-processes:\nService Capacity Management\nComponent Management\nBusiness Capacity Management",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) What is meant by the term OLA?",
        "answer": "The term OLA is a short form of 'Operational Level Agreement'. OLA is usually defined as the contract that emphasizes the different IT groups within the organization. This also defines how the various IT groups will design and deliver their services to support SLA (Service Level Agreement).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) What are some commonly used Recovery options?",
        "answer": "The following are the most commonly used Recovery options:\nFast Recovery: As the name suggests, this recovery option is speedy and takes place within 24 hours. It is also called a hot standby.\nIntermediate Recovery: This type of recovery mode usually takes a few days. Here, recovery possibly takes three to four days. It is referred to as warm standby as it used mirroring load balancing.\nGradual Recovery: This type of recovery may take a relatively long time. It can take a few weeks. But, the time will always exceed 24 hours in this recovery mode. It is also called a cold standby.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "37) What does the Freeze period mean in ITIL?",
        "answer": "The freeze period is defined as the specific time within the development process, after which the methods required to make changes to the source code seems much more difficult.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "38) What is defined by the term CAB?",
        "answer": "The term CAB is a short form of 'Change Advisory Board'. CAB involves a different authoritative and representative group of professionals who mainly help in Change Management. The CAB people assist with assessment, authorization, prioritization, and scheduling of the requested and the necessary changes whenever required.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Service Pipeline: It is defined as a listing of those services that are not yet ready and reside in the development mode.\nService Portfolio: It is defined as a listing of the comprehensive services offered by a service provider to the customers or shared throughout the entire market.\nService Catalog: It is defined as a listing of those services that have already been developed to be provided to the customers. It is known as the subset of the Service portfolio.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Expedite Change: It is a kind of change that meets a specified business or legal needs but does not relate to any restoring service.\nEmergency Change: It is a kind of change that is taken care of on a priority basis. It is considered a top priority change in any organization that must be implemented as quickly as possible.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "itil"
    }
]